(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-31T14:30:43.096154",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
奇跡のような
Like a miracle,
キミと作るメモリー
memories made with you.
ぎゅっと握りしめ 願ったよ
I held on tight and wished upon them.
きっと開花する ワクワクの新芽
Exciting new buds will surely bloom.
この場所が初めての 紡ぐ道標
This place is our first guiding post we weave.
ちょっとづつでも 踏み込んでみてね
Take a step forward, even if just a little.
幸せはすぐ傍にあるものだから
Because happiness is right by our side,
怯えないで 夢中になる
don't be afraid, lose yourself in it—
その力を… for you
use that power... for you.
この空に花咲かせてみせるよ
I'll make flowers bloom across this sky.
何より強い 生命の息
Stronger than anything, the breath of life.
涙は未来の味方になるから
Tears will become your ally in the future,
隣で拭いてあげる
so I'll wipe them away by your side.
小さな幸せが積もる未来へ
Toward a future where small happiness piles up—
la la… 口ずさむ安らぎは
la la... the comforting hum
足跡が語る 証の結晶
is a crystal of proof told by our footsteps.
次はキミが居るから
Next time, you will be there,
希望は無限だね
so hope is infinite.
一歩ずつから始めてみるよ
We'll start taking it one step at a time.
一緒に過ごして宝物より尊い
Spending time together, more precious than treasure,
夢の続きを 叶えて行こう
let's make the continuation of our dreams come true,
伝えて行こう… with you
let's convey it... with you.
散らばった
Scattered
刻のカケラ
fragments of time—
たとえチグハグだって かき集めれば
even if mismatched, if we gather them together,
ほら 新しいセカイ
look, a new world
開くはずだから
is bound to open.
今日も明日も
Today and tomorrow,
“ありがとう” 歌っていくよ
I will keep singing "Thank you."
鮮やかな花を咲かすために
To make vibrant flowers bloom,
大空へ満開にしてみせるよ
I'll make them burst into full bloom across the vast sky.
何より強い 生命の息
Stronger than anything, the breath of life.
涙は巡り味方になるから
Tears will come around and become your ally,
隣で拭いてあげる
so I'll wipe them away by your side.
小さな幸せが積もる未来へ
Toward a future where small happiness piles up—
奇跡のような
Like a miracle,
キミと作るメモリー
memories made with you.
奇跡のような毎日を 君と過ごしたいよ
I want to spend every day like a miracle with you
一緒に it's a wonderland
Together, it's a wonderland
憧れていた夢のせて 君の笑顔に会いに行きたいよ
Carrying the dream I longed for, I want to go meet your smile
大好きな気持ちだけ 変わらずに抱きしめて
Holding my fondest feelings close without change
魔法のようなキラキラ ずっと感じていたい の
I want to keep feeling that magical sparkle.
いま ファンタスティック 奇跡 ロマンティック
Now, fantastic, miraculous, romantic—
希望見せて 明日へ駆け抜けて
show me hope as we dash toward tomorrow!
そう ドーリシング集めて イルミネーション
Yes, gathering dreams, illumination,
探そう 夢のドア
let's search for the door of dreams.
明日もっと世界は輝くよ
Tomorrow, the world will shine even brighter,
キミ次第さ it's a wonderland
depending on you, it's a wonderland!
午前0時鐘が鳴る 素敵なお馬車で走るよ プリンセス
At midnight the bell rings, riding in a lovely carriage, a princess—
夜空から会いに行くよ 願いを込めて shooting star
I'll come meet you from the night sky, putting my wish into a shooting star.
踊る二人のユレマキ 伸びるシルエット
The swaying silhouette of the two dancing,
醒めないで夢の世界 もっと飛び跳ねていたい jump
don't wake up from the dream world, I want to keep jumping around!
いま ファンタスティック 奇跡 ロマンティック
Now, fantastic, miraculous, romantic,
驚いて笑わないで聞いて
don't be surprised or laugh, listen—
エヴリシング魅せれば エンターテインメント
if I show you everything, it's entertainment,
見つかる 夢のチケット
you'll find the ticket to dreams.
明日もっと世界は輝くよ
Tomorrow, the world will shine even brighter,
キミ次第さ it's a wonderland
depending on you, it's a wonderland!
イメージしてごめんね 空も飛べるはずだよ
Just imagine it, you should be able to fly in the sky too—
君がいるこの世界は 愛が溢れる
this world where you are overflows with love!
いま ファンタスティック 奇跡 ロマンティック
Now, fantastic, miraculous, romantic,
希望見せて 明日へ駆け抜けて
show me hope as we dash toward tomorrow!
そう ドーリシング集めて イルミネーション
Yes, gathering dreams, illumination,
探そう 夢のドア
let's search for the door of dreams.
明日もっと世界は輝くよ
Tomorrow, the world will shine even brighter,
キミ次第さ it's a wonderland
depending on you, it's a wonderland!
今日も無事お誕生日迎えることができたよ
I was able to safely celebrate my birthday today too,
みんなのおかげだ 本当に本当にありがとう
thanks to everyone, truly, truly thank you!
いま ファンタスティック 奇跡 ロマンティック
Now, fantastic, miraculous, romantic,
希望見せて 明日へ駆け抜けて
show me hope as we dash toward tomorrow!
そう ドーリシング集めて イルミネーション
Yes, gathering dreams, illumination,
探そう 夢のドア
let's search for the door of dreams.
好きになって！もっと！私を見て！もっと！
Fall in love with me! More! Look at me! More!
恩返しは “愛のこもった投げキッスで”
My repayment is "with a kiss thrown full of love"!
気のせいじゃない 目は 合っ てるよ
It's not your imagination, our eyes are meeting!
ハート 作って 恋し ちゃっ て ください！
Make a heart and fall in love, please!
やれること 何でも します
I'll do whatever it takes,
ＮＧ 無し で 体当たり 挑戦
taking on challenges head-on with no restrictions.
エゴサ で 見つけ た アンチ の コメ
The anti's comments I found through egosurfing—
ふざけんな ！ … 誰 より 分かっ てる し
"Cut the crap!" ...I understand that better than anyone,
でも 大丈夫 ステージ に 立て ば みんな が いる
but it's okay, once I stand on stage, everyone is here!
好き に なって ！ もっと ！ 私 見て ！ もっと ！
Fall in love with me! More! Look at me! More!
恩返し は “ 愛 の こもった 投げ キッス で ”
My repayment is "with a kiss thrown full of love"
嘘 に する ！ もっと ！ 夢 を 見せる ！ もっと ！
Making it a lie? More! Showing you dreams? More!
楽しん でって 愛 の こもった スペシャル ナイト
Enjoy this special night filled with love,
ファンサ し ちゃう ぞ
I'm going to give you fan service!
お手紙 も 書いて ください ！
Please write me letters too!
何度も 読んで 宝物 に します
I'll read them over and over and make them my treasure.
スキャンダル まだ 早い けど
A scandal is still too early, but
裏切り ませ ん ！ 宣言 し とき ます
I won't betray you! I'm making that declaration.
嫉妬 、 嫌がらせ に は 負け ない
I won't lose to jealousy or harassment,
ふざけんな ！ 実力 で 勝って やる
cut the crap! I'll win with pure skill.
だから 辞め ない 負けず嫌い 私 は いる
That's why I won't quit, as a sore loser, I am here!
好き に なって ！ もっと ！ 私 見て ！ もっと ！
Fall in love with me! More! Look at me! More!
恩返し は “ 愛 の こもった mona ビーム で ”
My repayment is "with a mona beam full of love"
大 歓声 ！ もっと ！ まだまだ ！ ねえ ？ もっと ！
Loud cheers! More! Still more! Hey? More!
受け止め て ね 愛 の こもった わがまま ソング
Accept it, please, this selfish song full of love.
ファンサ し ちゃう ぞ
I'm going to give you fan service!
はぁ … 終わり が 近づく 寂しい ね
Ah... the end is drawing near, it's so lonely.
楽しい のに 泣き そうだ よ
Even though it's fun, I feel like crying.
次 も 次 も また 会える よ ね ？
We can meet again and again, right?
優しさ に 満ちて いる 言葉 も 心 ない 誰か の 言葉 さえ も
Even words filled with kindness, even the heartless words of someone,
必要 なん だ 必要 なん だ 強く なろ う
they are necessary, they are necessary, I will become strong.
好き に 叫べ ！ もっと ！ 楽しんじまえ ！ もっと ！
Shout out your likes! More! Enjoy yourself to the fullest! More!
忘れないで 特別 な 日 に なる よう に
Don't forget, so that it becomes a special day,
共に 歌お う ずっと ！ 共に 歩も う ずっと ！
let's sing together forever! Let's walk together forever!
合言葉 は どっきびき の l ・ o ・ v ・ e
Our password is a heart-pounding l・o・v・e
好き に なって ！ もっと ！ 私 見て ！ もっと ！
Fall in love with me! More! Look at me! More!
恩返し は “ 愛 の こもった 投げ キッス で ”
My repayment is "with a kiss thrown full of love"
嘘 に する ！ もっと ！ 夢 を 見せる ！ もっと ！
Making it a lie? More! Showing you dreams? More!
楽しん でって 愛 の こもった スペシャル ナイト
Enjoy this special night filled with love,
ファンサ し ちゃう ぞ
I'm going to give you fan service!
もっと ！ まだまだ ！ ねえ ？ もっと ！
More! Still more! Hey? More!
もっと ！ 向け て くれ て も いい のに !
Even though you could direct more towards me!
愛 の こもった わがまま ソング
This selfish song full of love,
ファンサ し ちゃう ぞ
I'm going to give you fan service!
はぁ … 時間 が 近づく 寂しい ね
Ah... the time is drawing near, it's so lonely.
楽しい のに 泣き そうだ よ 次 も 次 も また 会える よ ね ？
Even though it's fun, I feel like crying. We can meet again and again, right?
優しさ に 満ちて いる 言葉 も 心 ない 誰か の 言葉 さえ も
Even words filled with kindness, even the heartless words of someone,
必要 なん だ 必要 なん だ 強く なろ う
they are necessary, they are necessary, I will become strong.
約束 ！
Promise!
はい！
Hey!
はい！はい！
Hey! Hey!
優しさに溢れている言葉も
Even words overflowing with kindness,
心ない誰かの言葉さえも
even the heartless words from someone,
必要なんだ
are necessary.
強く強くなろう
I will grow stronger.
好きに叫べ！もっと！楽しんじゃえ！もっと！
Shout your love! More! Enjoy yourself! More!
忘れずで 特別な日になりますように
Hoping this becomes an unforgettable, special day.
共に歌おう
Let's sing together
ずっと 共にあゆもう
forever, let's walk together forever.
ずっと 愛言葉は とびっきりの L・O・V・E
Our secret password is a dazzling L-O-V-E.
個性だけ！もっと！
Show your individuality! More!
私を見て！もっと！
Look at me! More!
音楽は 愛の籠った嘆きすで
My way of thanking you is with a loving kiss,
取りこにする もっと！夢を見せる！
to captivate you more, to show you dreams more!
もっと！楽しんでって！愛のこもった
Enjoy it more! A special night filled with love,
スペシャルナイト ファンサしちゃうぞ
I'll give you fan service!
ファンサしちゃうぞ
Fan service!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
はい！ということで皆さんこんにちは！ときのそらです！
Hi! So everyone, hello! I'm Tokino Sora!
今日は皆さん、えっと、えっと、ときのそら誕生日2021にしてくれてありがとうございます！
Thank you so much for celebrating Tokino Sora's Birthday 2021 with me today!
たくさんのコメントありがとう！見えてるよ、見えてるよ！
Thank you for all the comments! I see them, I see them!
いや、すごいね！
Man, it's amazing!
いや、久しぶりにこのね、ステージに来たんですけども、おぉ、すごいよね！もうやっぱりさ、アリーナって最高だよ！
I haven't been on this stage in a while, but wow, it's amazing! Being in the arena is simply the best!
こんな素敵なステージに立つことができて、私とっても幸せです！
I'm so happy to be able to stand on such a wonderful stage!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
お水を飲みたい！
I want to drink some water!
というわけですね、えっと、本日、は、なんか本当はね、え、今日ゲストの、え、アリスちゃん、コトネちゃん、青ちゃん、梓ちゃんと…
So, um, today, actually, originally, um, today's guests, Alice-chan, Kotone-chan, Ao-chan, Azuki-chan...
コトネちゃん以外アがついてる。今気づいた。
Everyone except Kotone has "a" in their name. I just noticed.
なんだけど、あの、ね、色々な事情があって、今日はね、一人でステージに立つことにはなっておりますが、
But, um, you know, due to various circumstances, I'll be standing on stage alone today,
その代わりにね、ちょっと4人には…
but instead, I thought I'd ask the four of them...
ちょっとある方法でお手伝いをね、してもらおうと思っていまして。まぁ、アリスちゃんはね、あの、実は一緒に踊って、みた、みたいな感じのをやりお手伝いだったので、ちょっとね、う、悲しいて感じなんだけど、
to help me out in a certain way. Alice-chan actually helped me film a dance video together, so I feel a bit sad about that,
でもでも、動画をたくさん盛り上げていこうかなと思っているので、ぜひぜひよろしくお願いします！
but I want to make the video super exciting, so I'd really appreciate your support!
というわけですね、そんな私の一番大切なお友達からメッセージが届いております！こちらです！
That being said, I've received a message from my dearest friend! Here it is!
ごきげんようです！そらちゃん！アリスだよ！
Good day! Sora-chan! It's Alice!
お誕生日おめでとうございます！
Happy birthday to you!
おめでとう！おめでとう！おめでとう！やったーー！おめでとう！
Congratulations! Congratulations! Congratulations! Yay! Congratulations!
あの、もうそらちゃんはいつでも、いつも優しくて、思いやりがあって、なんかアリスがこうやって話しかけると、そらちゃん「うぅん」って聞いてくれて、本当に本当に大好きです！
You know, Sora-chan is always so kind and caring, and whenever I talk to her, she listens with an "aww", and I really, really love her!
あの、そらちゃんはね、どんなにおとなさんになったとしても、そのままでそらちゃんいてください！これからもいっぱい、いっぱい仲良くしてもらえると嬉しいです！
You know, no matter how much of an adult Sora-chan becomes, please stay just the way you are! I'd be so happy if we could keep being super close from now on!
本当に！本当に！おめでとう！ありがとう！
Really! Really! Congratulations! Thank you!
いや、嬉しい！
Aw, I'm so happy!
アリスちゃん！メッセージありがとう！
Alice-chan! Thank you for the message!
そしてそして、アリスちゃんだけじゃなくってもう一人からも来てますよ！
And what's more, not just Alice-chan, a message from someone else has come too!
そらちゃん、お誕生日おめでとうございます！
Sora-chan, happy birthday!
こたねっち！えっと、そらちゃんとは、天神ことねです。
Kotenetch! Um, with Sora-chan, it's Tenjin Kotone.
えっとな、そらちゃんとはですね、3年半のお付き合い、お付き合いって言うか、3年半お友達期間を経ているのですけれども、初めは私が…
Um, Sora-chan and I have been friends for three and a half years... well, not "dating", but we've been friends for three and a half years. At first, I...
外のイベントとか番組に出たとき、隣の席だったことから始まって、
It started from when we sat next to each other at outside events and shows,
そこからずっとこうやって一緒にね、Vの界隈にいられることがすごく幸せだなってみんな思っています。ありがとう！
and I think everyone is so happy that we've been able to be together in the VTuber world ever since. Thank you!
最近は、ちょっとお互いの時間が合わなくて、電話したりとか話したりとか
Lately, our schedules haven't lined up well, so we haven't been able to call, talk,
配信一緒にやったりとかができてないけど、そろそろ私も落ち着いてきたから、また一緒に何かしようね！
or stream together, but things are calming down for me now, so let's do something together again!
そらちゃんのこれからがもっともっと幸せでありますようにって私も祈っております。はい！
I'm also praying that Sora-chan's future will be filled with more and more happiness. Yes!
というわけで、アリスちゃんとね、ことねちゃんのメッセージでした！ありがとうございます！
So those were messages from Alice-chan and Kotone-chan! Thank you so much!
そしてね、アリスちゃんとのね、ダンスの曲はね、ちょっとねソロになっちゃったんですけど、でもね、アリスちゃんの気持ちをね、ぐっと、ぐっと、こう、自分の心の中にいれて、パフォーマンスしていきたいと思います！
And for the dance song with Alice-chan, it ended up being a solo, but I want to put Alice-chan's feelings deep, deep inside my heart and perform it!
それでは聞いてください。エリアンエイリアン、そしてコネクト、2曲連続です！どうそ！
Now, please listen. "Alien Alien" and then "Connect," two songs in a row! Here we go!
ゆれる街灯 希う雨 降りる感情
Shaking streetlights, yearning rain, descending emotions,
感覚のテレパス 迷子のふたりはコンタクト
a sensory telepath, the lost pair makes contact.
ココロは恋を知りました タイトロープ
My heart has learned of love on a tightrope.
恋を知りました
It learned of love.
ツジハギの制服 重度のディスコミュニケーション
A patchwork uniform, severe discommunication,
眼光赤色にキラキラ 何かが起きる胸騒ぎ
eyes twinkling in crimson, a premonition that something's about to happen.
エイリアン わたしエイリアン あなたの心を惑わす
Alien, I'm an alien, leading astray your heart,
交ざりあう宇宙の引力で 感じてる気持ちはトキメキ
feeling this throbbing heart with the mingling gravity of the universe.
エイリアン あなたのエイリアン
Alien, your alien,
引きあう心は逃がされない
hearts pulling each other cannot escape.
あなたに未体験あげる 異世界の間まで
I'll give you an un-experience to the edge of another world,
トキメキ スキ
heart throbbing, love.
点灯と消灯を繰り返している蛍光灯
Fluorescent lights repeatedly turning on and off,
超常な混沌が静かにあなたを蝕んだ
paranormal chaos quietly eating into you.
並行な信号は特異点に因み交わった
Parallel signals intersected at a singularity,
創造現実盲信症感応性本能シンドローム
creation reality blind-faith sensitivity instinct syndrome.
ひとりきり夜な夜な空想描くまるでグリモア サーチライト避ける遊覧機
Alone night after night sketching daydreams like a grimoire, a floating craft avoiding searchlights.
「まだあなたはすべてを知りたい?」
"Do you still want to know everything?"
エイリアン わたしエイリアン
Alien, I'm an alien,
瞳に映らない引力に気づいてよ
notice the gravity not reflected in your eyes.
わたしはエイリアン
I am an alien.
エイリアン あなたのエイリアン
Alien, your alien,
触れ合えば傷は二度と消えない
touching each other, the wound will never fade away.
降りそそぐ無数の隕石も ときめく心には届かない!
Every meteor showering down cannot reach a throbbing heart!
エイリアン ふたりはエイリアン
Alien, the two of us are aliens,
高鳴る気持ちが抑えられない!
this pounding feeling cannot be held back!
あなたは未確認生命体 異世界の間まで
You are an unidentified life form, to the edge of another world,
あなたが好き
I love you.
エイリアン あなたのエイリアン
Alien, your alien,
見せたいのよあなたの知らない世界を
I want to show you a world you don't know.
交わした約束忘れないよ 目を閉じ確かめる
I won't forget the promise we made, I close my eyes and confirm it.
押し寄せた闇振り払って進むよ
I'll shake off the encroaching darkness and move forward.
いつになったらなくした未来を 私ここでまた見ることができるの?
When will I be able to see the lost future here again?
いつになったらなくした未来を
When will I be able to see the lost future...
私ここでまた見ることができるの?
here again?
交わした約束忘れないよ
I won't forget the promise we made,
目を閉じ確かめる
I close my eyes to be sure.
押し寄せた闇振り払って進むよ
I'll shake off the rushing darkness and press on.
いつになったらなくした未来を
When will I ever be able to see
私ここでまた見ることができるの?
that lost future right here once again?
溢れ出た不安の影を何度も裂いて
Shattering the overflowing shadows of doubt,
この世界歩んでいこう
let's walk through this world.
とめでなく刻まれた時は今始まり告げ
Time, ceaselessly ticking, now announces the start,
変わらない想いをのせ閉ざされた扉開けよう
Carrying unchanging feelings, let's open the closed door.
目覚めた心は走り出した
My awakened heart began to run,
未来を描くため
to sketch out the future.
難しい道で立ち止まっても空はきれいな青さでいつも待っていてくれる
Even if I stop on a tough road, the sky always waits in its pure blue,
だから怖くないもう何があっても挫けない
so I'm not afraid, I won't give up no matter what comes.
振り返れば仲間がいて
When I looked back, my friends were there,
気付けば優しく包まれてた
And before I knew it, I was wrapped in their warmth.
何もかもが歪んだ世界で唯一信じられるここが救いだった
In a distorted world, this place I could trust was my salvation.
喜びも悲しみも分け合えば強まる想い
If we share joy and sorrow, our feelings grow stronger.
この声が届くのならきっと奇跡はおこせるだろう
If this voice can reach you, I'm sure miracles can happen.
交わした約束忘れないよ目を閉じ確かめる
I won't forget the promise we made, I close my eyes to be sure.
押し寄せた闇振り払って進むよ
I'll shake off the rushing darkness and press on.
どんなに大きな壁があっても超えてみせるからきっと
No matter how huge the wall, I'll surely overcome it.
明日信じて祈って
Believing in tomorrow, praying.
どんなに大きな壁があっても超えてみせるからきっと
No matter how huge the wall, I'll surely overcome it.
明日信じて祈ろう
Believing in tomorrow, let's pray.
壊れた世界でさまよっては私は
Wandering in a broken world,
引き寄せられるように辿り着いた
I arrived as if drawn in.
目覚めた心は走り出した
My awakened heart began to run,
未来を描くため
to sketch out the future.
難しい道で立ち止まっても空はきれいな青さでいつも待っていてくれる
Even if I stop on a tough road, the sky always waits in its pure blue,
だから怖くないもう何があっても挫けない
so I'm not afraid, I won't give up no matter what comes.
ずっと明日待って
Always waiting for tomorrow.
というわけでエリアエリア！
And so, area-area!
そしてですね、かなちゃんと一緒に歌いました！
And we sang together with Kana-chan!
コネクトでした！
It was "Connect"!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
いやー、ということでね、今回は、おたよりのプレゼントをいただいたので、
So this time, since we received a gift of fan letters,
こう、デュエットみたいな感じでちょっと演出ができたらいいなと思って、
I thought it'd be nice to stage it like a duet,
こちらでね、こう一緒にデュエットみたいな感じの演出になっています。
so here we have a duet-style performance together.
いやー、なんかね、コネクトは一度ね、かなちゃんとも歌ったことのある曲で、
"Connect" is a song I once sang with Kana-chan too,
すごく思い出深かったので、私の方から、おお、ありがとう！
and it holds such dear memories, so from my end—oh, thank you!
から、ちょっと一緒にね、歌いたいなみたいな話をね、したんですよ。
I talked about how I wanted us to sing it together.
いやー、今回ね、本当にギリギリになっちゃったんですけど、こんな感じでプレゼントをもらえて本当に嬉しかったし、
It came down to the wire this time, but I was so happy to receive the present,
こう…
and...
今日はゲストが4人いるということなので、まだね、半分なんですよ。半分。
Since there are four guests today, we're still only halfway through! Halfway!
次、誰かのメッセージ来てるんだよ。
Next up, a message has arrived from someone.
誰だと思う？どっちだと思う？
Who do you think it is? Which one do you think?
早速見てみようか。
Let's take a look right away.
この方です！
It's this person!
こんそめー！あずきちことAZKiです。お誕生日おめでとう！
Consome! I'm Azkichi, AZKi. Happy birthday!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
あずきです。え、去年の誕生日から早い1年ですね。
It's Azuki. It's already been a year since last year's birthday, hasn't it?
こういう大変な状況の中でも、そらズで一緒にゲームをしたり、二人オリジナル曲を作ったり、
Even in this difficult situation, we played games together as Sora-z, made original songs for the two of us,
切なテイストふんだんに来る劇場版そらずがあったり、クリスマスライブもしたね。
had the emotional Theater version of Sora-z, and did a Christmas live.
えっと、そのあとは、そう、あの、マインクラフトをね、めっちゃそらちゃんが誘ってくれて、あずきがマインクラフト始めたりとか、
And after that, right, Sora-chan invited me so much to Minecraft, and I started playing Minecraft,
本当にそらちゃんと過ごしたこの1年間楽しい思い出がいっぱいです。
I really have so many fun memories of this past year spent with Sora-chan.
本当に本当にありがとう！とゆーわけで今日はね、え、そらちゃんとあの曲と、そらちゃんとあの曲、
Thank you so, so much! So today, um, with Sora-chan, that song and with Sora-chan, that song,
そしてあの曲を歌いたい…あれ？ね、みんなも聴きたいよね？ね？
and I want to sing that song... Huh? Right, everyone wants to hear it too, right? Right?
それでは改めてそらちゃんお誕生日おめでとう！これからも仲良くしてね。そして今年も1年素敵な年にしてください。それではあずきでした！どーん！
So once again, Happy Birthday Sora-chan! Please keep being good friends with me. And please make this year a wonderful year too. Well then, it was Azuki! Boom!
はい、ということで、あずきちゃんからメッセージもらったよ！ありがとう！
Yes, so I got a message from Azuki-chan! Thank you!
嬉しいな。嬉しいな。
I'm so happy. I'm so happy.
もう嬉しくてなんかもうこのあと行きたくない感じ、うそ。
I'm so happy I feel like I don't want to go on after this... just kidding.
それでは、このあとの曲いきましょうか。今ね、この曲とこの曲って言ってたんですけど、え、私たちにはですね、オリジナル曲が２つあります。
Well then, shall we go to the next song? Just now, I was saying 'this song and that song', but, uh, we have two original songs.
その２つをですね、メドレーで歌っていきたいと思います。
We'd like to sing those two in a medley.
まず1曲目、こちらです！刹那ティックコード。
First song, here it is! 'Setsuna Tick Code'.
いつだって未来のためばかりに
Always just for the sake of the future,
今という時間を費やすけれど
spending all my time on the present,
今だけは今だけを感じ合うことができたら
If only we could feel just this moment, right now,
OFFにして断ち切った ココロがもう一度動き出すよ
the heart we turned off and cut off starts moving once again!
震え出そうな胸の痛みも 涙の理由（わけ）もすべて
Even the trembling pain in my chest, and the reason for my tears, all of it
強さに変えて
turning into strength.
飲み込んだ想い 仰いだ空に飛ばせ
Send the swallowed feelings flying into the upturned sky,
繋がるメロディー 流れる星に変わっていく
the connecting melody transforms into a shooting star.
キミのために歌うよ キミに届くようにと
I'll sing for you, so that it reaches you,
輝きは世界軸を超えていく
and its brilliance transcends the axis of the world.
確かにココで重ね合えた和音（コード） 触れ合う音が光になって降り注ぐ
The chords we surely layered together here, the touching sounds turn into light and pour down,
この一瞬が永遠だと 煌めいては色づいてゆく キミと描いた空間（セカイ）
this moment is eternal, sparkling and coloring the space we drew together.
いつだって 明日は来るだなんて
As if tomorrow will always come—
来てほしくない朝もあるけど
though there are mornings I don't want to come—
夜の闇息潜め このまま隠れられなくて
hiding our breath in the darkness of night, unable to stay hidden like this,
静寂を断ち切って 叫びたい声を歌に変えた
we cut through the silence and turned the voice we wanted to shout into a song.
いつもそこにある 隔て阻む 壁も壊して進め
Move forward, breaking down the walls that always stand and block our way,
胸の奥にある 忘れたふりで誤魔化し切れない 傷も乗り越えていく
overcoming even the injuries deep in our hearts that we couldn't completely gloss over by pretending to forget.
絡まった想い 音に変えて飛ばせ
Send the entangled feelings into sound and let them fly,
生まれるメロディー 激しく鼓動共鳴で合う
the melody that is born resonates violently with our heartbeats.
言葉だけじゃ足りない 歌いじゃなくちゃ届かない
Words alone aren't enough, without singing it won't reach,
情熱が胸を熱くさせていく
passion makes the heart burn hotter.
確かにココで分かり合えたpassword（コード）
The password we could surely understand together here,
時の流れも逆らうように拓かれる
opened up as if defying the flow of time.
何度だって歌うから キミの場所がいつでも光に包み込まれるように
I'll sing as many times as it takes, so that your place is always embraced in light.
乱れる 何度もだって歌うから
No matter how many times it gets chaotic, I'll keep singing,
君の場所が いつも光に包み込まれるように
so that your place is always enveloped in light.
すべてが崩れ出した ここで
Here where everything began to crumble,
どこにも歩き出せない 時は
when I can't walk anywhere at all,
贈り続けるこの言葉も 聞こえる場所探し 飛び出すよ
I'll leap out to find a place where these words I keep giving can still be heard.
遠くの星が 瞬くように いつも何かを伝えるように 歌える
Like distant stars twinkling, always conveying something, I can sing.
飲み込んだ想い 青い空に
My swallowed feelings, into the blue sky,
飛ばせ 繋がるメロディ 流れる星に留まってく
let them fly—connected melodies linger on shooting stars.
君のために歌うよ 君に届くようにと
I'll sing for you, so that it reaches you.
輝きは 境目を越えて
The radiance crosses the boundaries,
確かにここで重なり合えたこと 触れ合う音が光になって降り注ぐ
and the fact that we truly overlapped here—our touching sounds become light pouring down.
この一瞬が 永遠だと
Believing this very moment is eternal,
煌めいてはいろづいていく 君と描いたセカイ
it sparkles and colors up—the world we painted together.
君と描く 音飛び出す 絶えずここまでの
The sound we paint leaps out, endlessly up to here...
紅藍クロニクル
Kurenai Chronicle
雲間に隠れた 夢の星よ
Oh star of dreams hidden among the clouds,
今君は どこで輝いているんだろう
where are you shining right now?
今夜を彷徨う 無数の風が
Countless winds wandering through tonight
今僕をどこかへ連れて行くよ
are taking me somewhere right now.
僕らが支え合うため 世界中で共に生きてくため
So that we can support each other, so that we can live together in this world,
交わる霧 歌うきらり
intersecting mist, singing brilliantly.
ただこの空の先 どこまででも呼び覚ませ心の奥にあるものを
Just beyond this sky, no matter how far, awaken what is deep within your heart.
闇を切り裂く 飛び立つように
Like tearing through the darkness, taking flight,
果てない夜が 闇を貫く 煌めく光になれ
endless night pierces the darkness—become a glittering light.
悲しさよ 寂しさの 雨に打たれても
Even if beaten by the rain of sadness and loneliness,
辿り着く音 確かなメロディ それはきっと嘘じゃないよ
the sound we reach, the certain melody—that is surely no lie.
ここで いつまでも いつまでも 二人歌おう
Right here, forever and ever, let the two of us sing.
誰にも見せない 弱さがほら
The weakness we show to no one, look,
こぼれては 力に変わっていくから
spilling over, transforms into strength.
誰かを信じる 勇気はもう
The courage to believe in someone
振り切って 前へと進むだけだ
is already shaken off—just pressing forward.
僕らの存在は 価値あるもので変わりなんていない
Our existence is valuable, irreplaceable.
言えるんだって だって この魂は
We can say that, because this soul
本物だ 打ちくだけ 理不尽も 常識も
is real—smash through unreason and conventional wisdom alike.
壁を越えて 逆らうように 果てない役目は 胸を貫く
Surpassing walls, defying them—an endless role pierces the heart.
脈打つ血潮になれ 愛しさや 切なさも
Become pulsing lifeblood, remembering even the loveliness and pain.
覚えていくの 作り出す音
The sounds we create—
確かなハーモニー これは生きがいだから声を聴かせてよ
a definite harmony, because this is our reason to live—let us hear your voice.
二人歌おう
Let the two of us sing.
いつだって未来のためばかり
Even if we spend time only for the future,
今という時間を費やすけれど
spending our time on the present,
今だけは今だけを感じ合うことができたら
if we could just feel the present moment now—
OFFにして断ち切ったココロがもう一度動き出すよ
turn it off and cut it off, our hearts start moving once again.
震え出そうな胸の痛みも涙の理由もすべて
The trembling pain in our chests, the reasons for our tears,
強さに変えて
turning them all into strength,
飲み込んだ想い仰いだ空に飛ばせ
we swallow our feelings and let them fly to the gazing sky.
繋がるメロディー流れる星に変わっていく
Connecting melodies transform into flowing stars.
キミのために歌うよキミに届くようにと
I'll sing for you, so it reaches you.
輝きは世界軸を超えていく
Brilliance transcends the world's axis.
確かにしてここで重ね合えたコード
A chord we successfully overlapped right here.
触れ合う音が光になって降り注ぐ
Touching sounds turn into light and pour down.
この一瞬が永遠にと煌めいては色づいていく
This single moment sparkles and colors up as eternity.
キミと描いたセカイ
The world we sketched together.
いつだって朝は来るんだなんて
Morning always comes, they say,
来てほしくない朝もあるけど
though there are mornings I don't want to come.
夜の闇潜みこのまま隠れられなくて
Lurking in the darkness of the night, unable to hide away,
静寂を断ち切って叫びたい声を歌に変えた
breaking through the silence, I turned my desire to shout into a song.
いつもそこにある隔て阻む壁も壊して進め
Breaking through the barriers that are always there, let's move forward.
胸の奥にある忘れたふりで誤魔化し切れない傷も
Even wounds we pretended to forget and couldn't fully misinterpret,
乗り越えていく
we will ride past them.
絡まった想い音に変えて飛ばせ
Entangled feelings turned into sound and sent flying,
生まれるメロディー激しく鼓動奏で合う
the newborn melody beats passionately and harmonizes.
言葉だけじゃ足りない歌いじゃなくちゃ届かない
Words alone aren't enough, singing alone won't suffice;
情熱が胸を熱くさせていく
passion warms my chest.
確かにしてここで分かり合えたコード
A chord where we understood each other right here.
時の流れも逆らうように拓かれる
Bending the flow of time as if defying it.
はい!というわけで
Right then, hey!
あずきちと歌ったのは
The two songs AZKi and I just sang were
眠れないクロニクル、そして切なティックコードの2曲でした。
"Fuminai Chronicle" and "Setsunatick Code".
ありがとう!
Thank you!
いやあ、この2つの曲はね
Well, these two songs, you know,
なんか私の中ではすごい挑戦というか
for me, it was quite a challenge, so to speak.
あんまりね、普段そのかっこいい歌を歌っていなかったので
I haven't really sung such cool songs before,
なんかすごく、なんか頑張ったなっていう
so I felt like I really worked hard.
イメージがある曲というか
Kind of songs that leave an impression.
まあね、あずきちとはね、あの
Well, AZKi and I, you know,
それぞれ一人一人、活動しているときに
each of us doing our own solo activities,
こう一緒にね、頑張っていこう、頑張っていこうって
when we're together like, "Let's do our best, let's do our best!"
こう切磋琢磨してきた中なんだけど
striving and improving ourselves.
そんなね、あずきちちゃんとの曲をこう一緒にね歌うことができて
So being able to sing songs together with AZKi-chan like this,
っていう形ですが、とっても嬉しいなと思えました。
makes me so happy.
あずきちちゃん曲作ってるんで、すごいよね。
AZKi-chan creates those songs,
もう才能にあふれてるよ。
She's overflowing with talent.
お水飲むね、ちょっと。
Let me drink some water, hold on.
ふふっ
(Laughs)
急にお水飲みたいぶ、よいしょ。
Suddenly wanting to drink water, whoops.
よいしょってなんだ。
"Whoops" is random.
わあ、なんだ、お水、お水ありがとうみんな。
Ah, water, thanks everyone.
ええ、というわけでね、まあね、あずきちの曲2つはね
So, AZKi's two songs,
自分でも歌いやすいキーにはなっていたので
since they were songs that I personally found easy to sing,
今までこう歌った中では一番こう安心し...
among the ones I've sung so far,
歌えたなっていう感じもしますし
I felt I could sing them with peace of mind.
こうね、ここにね、ずっとあずきちがね見守ってくれてると思ったら
And thinking that AZKi has been watching over me here all this time,
なんかリラックスしちゃった、今。
I relaxed too much.
今リラックスしすぎて、すごいまったりの喋ってるんですけど
I relaxed so much I started talking too leisurely,
まあね、まったりの喋ってるわけにもいかないぞと
but well, I can't just keep chatting idly.
いうわけでですね、最後のメッセージ行きましょうか。
So, let's move on to the final message!
歌いやすいです、歌いやすい。
It's easy to sing, very easy.
全然、高い、高いかな?
Actually, is it high?
私のエリアエリアよりは低いから。
It's lower than my usual aria range,
でも全然、どの曲も歌いやすい曲を選んでるんですけど、ライブなので。
though I always choose songs that are easy to sing for lives.
あ、そういうこと言ってる場合じゃない。次のメッセージ、見てみましょう!
Ah, wait, that's not it. Let's look at the next message!
どん!
Ta-da!
そらちゃん、お誕生日おめでとうございます!
Sora-chan, happy birthday!
気合が入ってる、テロップに気合が入ってる、ありがとうイェーイ!
I'm getting so pumped up! My energy is through the roof!
ね、今日は大事な生誕祭に呼んでくれてありがとう!
Thank you for inviting me to such an important birthday live today!
そらちゃんとの一番の思い出は
Sora-chan and my number one memory...
うた
was...
と、言いたいところだけど
Well, I wanted to say...
前にね、お絵かきコラボしたときに
earlier, when we did a drawing collab,
そらちゃんが描いた得体の知れないザリガニのような何かが
Sora-chan drew something like an unfathomable crawfish,
今でも脳裏にこびりついて離れません。
and it's still stuck in my brain and won't leave.
そらちゃんはよくモノマネされることが多いと思うんだけど
Sora-chan is often imitated by others, I think,
うちはどうしても何回練習してもそらちゃんのモノマネがうまくできません。
but no matter how many times I practice, I just can't master Sora-chan's impression.
でも今日は大事なお誕生日なので
Today is such an important birthday,
全集中、ときの呼吸参ノ型でモノマネしたいと、思います。
so I want to try imitating Sora's Breathing, Third Form!
耳の穴かっぽじって、ぜひ聞いてね!
Clear out your ears and listen closely, okay?
ときん…
Tokin...
似てたかなあ?
Did that sound like her?
それではそらちゃん、本当にお誕生日おめでとうございます!
Well, Sora-chan, truly, happy birthday!
AZKiでした!
It was AZKi!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
なんかいろいろツッコミどころなるメッセージだったんだけど、
There were lots of things to comment on in that message,
すごくすごく青いちゃんらしいなと思って、嬉しいなって思いました。
but I thought it was so very Aoi-chan, and it made me so happy.
ありがとう！
Thank you!
時の…ほら、3の肩って言ってた？
Tokino... wait, did she say \"3's shoulder\"?
ふー、イエーイとかも凄かったね。
Man, the cheers and \"yeahs\" were amazing too.
そんなね、葵ちゃんとはね、実はね、あるデュエット曲を歌いたいなと思ってるんですよ。
And actually, Aoi-chan and I, we've been wanting to sing a certain duet song together.
うーん、何だと思う？ 初めて2人で歌うので、ぜひぜひ皆さん
Hmm, what do you think it is? It's our first time singing together as a duo, so everyone,
しっかり耳の穴かっぽじって、や、ぜひ聞いてください！
please open your ears wide and definitely listen to it!
それでは2人で歌います、チューリングラブ！
Now then, we'll sing it together: Turing Love!
あー、恋の定義がわからない
Ah, I don't know the definition of love
まずスキって基準もわからない
First of all, I don't know the standard for \"like\"
要は恋してる時が恋しい
In short, I yearn for the times when I'm in love
客観？主観？エビデンスプリーズ！
Objective? Subjective? Evidence please!
愛は計算じゃ解けない
Love cannot be solved by calculation
まず普通の計算も解けない
First, I can't even solve ordinary calculations
要はそんな状態が愛らしい
In short, that kind of state is adorable
大概の大事象においてQがあってAを出して解けるのに
Even though most major events have a Q and A to solve them
勘違いって間違って 解のないこの気持ちはなんだろう
What is this feeling without an answer, born from misunderstandings?
(検証は不明瞭)
(Verification is unclear)
Dazing!! モーションは相対性にステイ
Dazing!! Motion stays in relativity
チューリングラブ 見つめあったって解けないメロウ
Turing Love - a mellow mood that won't resolve even by staring
ワッツアイラブ いま123で証そうか
What's I Love - shall we prove it now in 1, 2, 3?
言葉で生み出すクエストョン (クエストョン!)
Questions generated with words (Question!)
ハートで高鳴るアンサー (アンサー!)
Answers echoing with a beating heart (Answer!)
測ったって不確定性 ぼくらのBPM
Uncertainty measured by our BPM
チューリングラブ 宙に舞ったって信じられないけど
Turing Love - even if we flew in the air, I can't believe it
フォリンラブ 今はABCすらバグりそうだな
Falling Love - right now even ABC seems to be glitching
なんでか教えてオイラー (オイラー!)
Tell me why, Euler (Euler!)
感想きかせてフェルマー (フェルマー!)
Tell me your thoughts, Fermat (Fermat!)
予測不可能性に触れてみる
Let's touch upon the unpredictability
さあ証明しよう (証明しよう)
Now let's prove it (Let's prove it)
間違いのないように証明しよう (証明しよう)
Let's prove it without any mistakes (Let's prove it)
この感情全部全部証明しよう (証明しよう)
Let's prove all these emotions (Let's prove it)
正解があるなら証明しよう (証明しよう)
If there's a correct answer, let's prove it (Let's prove it)
シンプルなQ.E.D.
A simple Q.E.D.
ASAP! 導き出したい 最適解へ
ASAP! I want to reach the optimal solution
何度空回ったって ぶつかっちゃったって
No matter how many times we spun our wheels or collided,
不思議なこのアノマリーを解き明かす 過程さえ必要条件です
even the process of unraveling this mysterious anomaly is a necessary condition
3次元(空間)における2点AB間の距離を求めよ
\"Find the distance between two points A and B in 3D space.\"
特徴的な感じだと思ってたのに
I thought it was a typical feeling,
参考資料にも載っていないから 君と見出して見せたいじゃん
but it's not in the reference materials, so I want to find it with you
3次元(世界)におけるこの気持ちの求め方
How to calculate this feeling in a 3D world
丸だってバツだって不安にとってイクォールで
Circles and crosses are equal to anxiety
近づいて遠くなって揺れるこの気持ちのハーモニー
The harmony of these feelings swaying closer and farther
チョーキングメロディ
Choking melody
ステディモーションは素直アイズミステイク
Steady motion is an honest mistake of the eyes
チューリングラブ ざわめき出した胸、眠りたくなるほど
Turing Love - my chest started to buzz, almost making me want to sleep
証明は 今も格闘増して いるような
It feels like the proof is still struggling more and more
曖昧も超越して最大の仮説を 今ふたりなら実証できそう
Transcending ambiguity, if it's the two of us now, we can prove the biggest hypothesis
チューリングラブ 見つめあったって切りないメロウ
Turing Love - an endless mellow mood from gazing at each other
ワッツアイラブ いま123で証そうか
What's I Love - shall we prove it now in 1, 2, 3?
言葉で生み出すクエストョン (クエストョン!)
Questions generated with words (Question!)
ハートで高鳴るアンサー (アンサー!)
Answers echoing with a beating heart (Answer!)
測ったって不確定性 ぼくらのBPM
Uncertainty measured by our BPM
チューリングラブ 瞬きたってその因果の
Turing Love - even when blinking, its causality
フォリンラブ 結局は今で分かりそうさ
Falling Love - we'll probably figure it out right now
確かめさせてピタゴラス (ピタゴラス!)
Let me confirm, Pythagoras (Pythagoras!)
確信させてリーマン (リーマン!)
Make me certain, Riemann (Riemann!)
予測不能な変生に今触れてみる
Let's touch upon the unpredictable transformation
さあ証明しよう (証明しよう)
Now let's prove it (Let's prove it)
間違いのないように証明しよう (証明しよう)
Let's prove it without any mistakes (Let's prove it)
この感情全部全部証明しよう (証明しよう)
Let's prove all these emotions (Let's prove it)
正解があるなら証明しよう (証明しよう)
If there's a correct answer, let's prove it (Let's prove it)
推測を超えて証明しよう (証明しよう)
Let's prove it beyond guesswork (Let's prove it)
違いのないように証明しよう (証明しよう)
Let's prove it without any differences (Let's prove it)
推測を超えて証明しよう (証明しよう)
Let's prove it beyond guesswork (Let's prove it)
証明しよう (証明しよう)
Let's prove it (Let's prove it)
この感情全部全部証明しよう (証明しよう)
Let's prove all these emotions (Let's prove it)
正解があるなら証明しよう (証明しよう)
If there's a correct answer, let's prove it (Let's prove it)
シンプルなQ.E.D.
A simple Q.E.D.
はーい！
Yay!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
映像もプレゼントしてくれた！
She even gave me a video as a present!
葵ちゃーん！見てたよー！ありがとう！
Aoi-chan! I was watching! Thank you!
みんな、みんな、すごくこう、私の、こう、なんていうんだろう、お誕生日に協力してくれて、もう感謝でいっぱいです！
Everyone, everyone, I'm just so full of gratitude to you all for helping out with my birthday!
はー、嬉しいね！
Ah, I'm so happy!
あ、どういうことです？
Ah, what do you mean?
えっと、こうか。
Um, like this?
皆さん、どうだったでしょうか？
Everyone, how was it?
いやー、私的にはとっても最高だったし、こんなにたくさんの皆さんと、こう
Man, for me, it was such an amazing birthday,
and being able to spend time with so many of you...
みんなとね、こう、一緒に時間を過ごすことができて、本当に幸せだったなって思います。
and share this time together,
I truly feel so happy.
Thank you for...
Thank you... Pat-pat, everyone!
Pat-pat, everyoneってなに？
What's "pat-pat, everyone"?
Clap, everyone!
Thank you! Thank you!
ということでですね、お誕生日、本当に最高の
So, my birthday truly was the most...
え、ライブにみんなのおかげで、もちろん
Um, thanks to everyone's support, of course...
一緒に協力してくださったゲストのみんな、そしてここにいるスタッフの皆さん、本当にありがとうございます！
All the guests who collaborated with us,
and everyone on the staff here, thank you so much!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
そして、何よりもここに応援してくださっている皆さんの、おかげだなって思ってます。本当にみんな今日はありがとう！
And above all, I feel like this is all thanks
to everyone cheering me on here. Thank you all today!
そしてそして、最後になるんですが、ええ、最後の曲の前に、ちょっとですね
And finally, before the very last song,
um, I have a little...
告知、急になんか告知みたいになっちゃったんですけど、え、私、お誕生日ということで、え、記念グッズの方を、え、出させていただくことになりました！
...announcement! It suddenly turned into an announcement,
but since it's my birthday, I'm releasing commemorative merchandise!
それがこちらです！
And here it is!
はい、ときのそら誕生日記念2021、え、5月15日販売開始ということで、この後21時から販売させていただきます。
Yes, the Tokino Sora Birthday Commemoration 2021
goes on sale May 15th, available starting at 9 PM tonight!
え、そちらの方ですね、セットになっておりまして、記念ボイス1種、そして記念グッズ3種セット。
Um, that will be available as a set, featuring
one commemorative voice set and three merchandise items.
そしてですね、え、直筆サイン入りで、数量限定なんですけども、オロダ生生が書き下ろしのイラストポストカードの方をご用意しております。
And we also have an autographed, limited-quantity
illustration postcard drawn by Oruda-sensei!
え、こちらの方ですね、ぜひぜひ、あのこの後21時からということなので、気になる方は見ていただけると嬉しいです。ま、1つ1つのものをちょっと見ていきましょう。こちらです！
It goes on sale at 9 PM tonight, so I'd be so happy
if you checked it out. Let's look at each item! Here it is!
まずこちら、オリジナルCD、その名が「KumoHurry!」ということでですね、え、これから歌うKumoHurry!の曲なんですけども、こちらの曲は私が作詞しまして、赤汀さんに作曲していただきました。
First is this original CD, titled "KumoHurry!".
It was written by me and composed by Akaji-san.
え、そしてですね、2つ目のほうは「花時の空」という曲なんですけども、こちらこの時空の空、と、言ってですね、あの、最初の、本当に、まだね一人ぼっちで寂しいなと思いながらやっていたときに、ロジラロジックさんという方から、え、提供された曲です。
And the second one is "Hana toki no sora",
provided by Logila Logic back when I was still all alone.
え、それをですね、フルバージョンで収録しております。こちらのあとインストと、え、何でしょう、あのインストも入っている全4曲になっております。
We've recorded the full version,
along with the instrumental, making 4 tracks in total.
え、こちらがですね、えっと、ここから、まあ、全部かな？単品でも、でも買えるようになっておりまして、こちらのほうはミニぬいぐるみになっております。
You can buy these as a set or individually.
This one is a mini plushie!
え、ミニぬいぐるみのほうは、えっと、やっぱね、こう、今までのぬいぐるみと違ってちょっとちっちゃめなんですよね。だからなんか、こう、机に飾れるみたいなやつもあるし。
The mini plushie is a bit smaller than usual,
so you can display it on your desk.
まあね、大きいそらちゃんに囲まれてちっちゃいぬいぐるみポンって乗っけてもらってもうれしいし、カバンにつけてもらってもうれしいかなということで、ちょっとね。
It'd make me happy if you placed it surrounded by
bigger Sora-chans or attached it to your bag.
ぬいぐるみ、ぬいぐるみ、ぬいぐるみ、みたいな感じで飾ってもらえたらいいなと思いまして、こちらにいたしました。はい！
I thought it'd be cute to display it like
"plushie, plushie, plushie!", so that's why I chose this.
え、これすごくない？オロダ先生書き下ろし両面クリアファイル！これもね、もちろん単品で買えますよということでね、両面すごいかわいいでしょ！
A double-sided clear file newly illustrated by Oruda-sensei!
You can buy this individually too, and both sides are super cute!
あの、ねえ、テンションが上がっている、こうふわっとしてる私と、あと花時の空をイメージした、こう私のクリアファイルの、こう両面になっておりますので、ぜひぜひね、使っていただけたら嬉しいなと。
It's double-sided with me feeling all fluttery
and excited on one side, and an image inspired by the song.
学校とか会社とかでね、ちょっと使いやすいかなと思って、A4のクリアファイルになっておりますので、ぜひぜひちょっと見てみてください。私もこれ、何個か買って1個使う（笑）。
I thought it'd be useful at school or work
since it's A4 size. I'll buy a few and use one myself!
こちらはですね、え、記念ボイスですね。
And this here is the commemorative voice set.
記念ボイスも、記念ボイスだけで買うのかな？ボイスの方と、あと全部セットの方は、えーと、数量限定になっております。これ全部合わせたものになりますね。
You can buy the voice set on its own,
and the all-in-one set is available in limited quantities.
こちらのほうは直筆でサインかかせていただきますので、ぜひぜひ興味ある方はよろしくお願いします！
For this set, I'll be signing them myself,
so please check it out if you're interested!
皆さん、わかったかな？がんばってって言われてる。何を？何を頑張るの？
Did everyone get it? Someone said "Do your best!"
What? What should I do my best at?
ありがとう
Thank you.
おっし、ありがとうみんな！
Alright, thank you everyone!
というわけでね、21時から、えー
So, starting from 9 PM, um...
ちょっとみんなこう、見て待ってもらえれば嬉しいなと思います。
I'd be really happy if you all could check it out and wait.
そして次歌う曲は、その2曲のうちの雲晴れのほうを歌わせていただきます。
And the next song I'll be singing is KumoHurray, one of those two songs.
こちらのの方はですね、掛け声がたくさんあります。初めて歌うのでどうなるか分かりませんが、掛け声に気づいたらコメントしてもらえると嬉しいです。
This one has lots of call-and-response cheers. Since it's my first time singing it, I'm not sure how it'll go, but I'd be happy if you comment when you notice them.
すごい難しい曲なので頑張って歌います。
It's a really difficult song, so I'll do my best.
それではもう最後の曲いっちゃって大丈夫ですかね？
Well then, is it alright if we go straight to the final song?
最後の曲いこうと思います。
I think we'll go with the final song.
今日初公開作詞いたしました、雲晴れ！
Today I'm premiering lyrics I wrote: KumoHurray!
雲晴れ！
KumoHurray!
さあ！前へ進め！
Now! Let's move forward!
ふわふわっとリズムに合わせてステップ踏んでいこう
Stepping to the fluffy rhythm,
どこまででも羽ばたいていけそうさ
We can soar anywhere!
ドキドキ ワクワク 胸が高鳴るよ
Heart pounding, thrilled, my heart beats fast!
この想いはもうとまらない
These feelings won't stop anymore.
みんな元気に行こうよ
Let's all go energetically!
大きい声出して叫ぼう！
Shout out with a big voice!
心が軽くなっていくからさ
Because our hearts will feel lighter.
君の心は曇りのち晴れ渡って 虹をかけるよ
Your cloudy heart clears up into sunny skies, arching a rainbow.
胸を張って今を進もう
Let's walk forward today with our heads held high.
星のように輝いて
Shining like the stars.
ぬんぬんっと呼吸を合わせて
Aligning our breathing together,
気持ち読んでこう、いたずらもしあえたらいいよね！
Let's share our feelings, teasing each other along the way!
じゃあ、敵だね？（ヤメテヨ）うそだね！（そっかー）
Well then, are we enemies? (Stop it!) Just kidding! (I see!)
ささやかな会話でわたしたちは今わかりあう
Through casual conversation, we understand each other now.
越えていこうあのときのそらよりももっと遠くまで
Let's go beyond, even further than that time's sky.
みんなを置いていかないからね
Because I won't leave you all behind.
さあ、止まらないで
Now, don't stop.
うわのそらにならないで歩けたなら
If you could walk without being absent-minded,
ゆっくりでも道はできる
A path will form even if it's slow.
夢の色を描いて
Painting the colors of our dreams.
曇りがちな気分もちょっと目線を変えたなら
Even a gloomy mood brightens if you change your perspective,
心晴れ晴れ明るくなれるかもよ？
Your heart might become bright and sunny.
1人じゃないよ
You're not alone.
不安になったらここにくればいいよ
If you feel uneasy, you can come here.
わたしはずっと待っているからね
Because I'll always be waiting.
負けてもいい
It's okay to lose.
がんばってきたことは無駄じゃないから
Because everything you've worked hard for isn't in vain.
胸を張って今を生きていこう
Let's live in the present with our heads held high.
星のように輝いて
Shining like the stars.
ぬんぬんっと呼吸を合わせて
Aligning our breathing together,
気持ち読んでこう、いたずらもしあえたらいいよね！
Let's share our feelings, teasing each other along the way!
じゃあ、敵だね？（ヤメテヨ）
Well then, are we enemies? (Stop it!)
うそだね！（そっかー）
Just kidding! (I see!)
ささやかな会話でわたしたちは今わかりあう
Through casual conversation, we understand each other now.
越えていこうあのときのそらよりももっと遠くまで
Let's go beyond, even further than that time's sky.
みんなを置いていかないからね
Because I won't leave you all behind.
さあ、止まらないで
Now, don't stop.
うわのそらにならないで歩けたなら
If you could walk without being absent-minded,
ゆっくりでも道はできる
A path will form even if it's slow.
夢の色を描いて
Painting the colors of our dreams.
曇りがちな気分もちょっと目線を変えたなら
Even a gloomy mood brightens if you change your perspective,
心晴れ晴れ明るくなれるかもよ？
Your heart might become bright and sunny.
1人じゃないよ
You're not alone.
ありがとうございました！
Thank you very much!